Preliminary Inventory of the Henry Bancroft Smith Papers, 1919-1928
Hoover Institution Archives
Henry Bancroft Smith Papers,
1919-1928
57006
Smith, Henry Bancroft, 1884-
28 manuscript boxes, 1 cubic foot box 12.7 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Diaries, correspondence, reports, memoranda, financial records, printed matter, and photographs, relating to American food relief in Europe, economic reconstruction in Poland, and agricultural market conditions in Europe.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1957.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
United States. Dept. of Commerce.; United States Grain Corporation.; Agriculture--Europe.; Reconstruction (1914-1939)--Poland.; Technical assistance, American--Poland.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; Europe.; Poland.; Poland--Economic conditions--1918-1945.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Commerce.; Commercial attachés.
Container List
- Accounts (Box 1)
  - Henry Bancroft Smith, Special Representative, London, U.S. Department of Commerce, 1922-1925, Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce
  - Henry Bancroft Smith, Special Representative, also personal correspondence, military papers, 1923-1927 (Box 2)
- Correspondence (incoming and outgoing) (Box 3)
  - Food Administration, correspondence, 1919 - Department of Commerce, 1921
  - Henry Bancroft Smith as acting Commercial Attaché, Poland, 1922-1923, also Special Representative, Department of Commerce, 1923 (Box 4)
  - Personal, also re European Crop yields, statistics, etc., London, 1924 (Box 5)
  - With Julius H. Barnes, Julius Klein, and many others, London, 1925-1926 (Box 6)
  - London, 1926-1928 (Box 7)
- Agricultural Markets Section (Box 8)
- Cables - Bureau (Box 9)
- Countries, misc. (Box 10)
- Danzig (Box 11)
- Miscellaneous correspondence; report to President Coolidge by Herbert Hoover re U.S. St. Lawrence Commission (Commerce period); Smith - miscellaneous manuscripts; Taylor - articles; books (Russian orange book, Austrian red book, British documents) (Box 12)
- Letters to Bureau (Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce, 1922, Warsaw, Poland, 1922-1929, London, 1926-1927, Department of Commerce, Washington, D.C.) re accounts (Box 13)
- Letters to Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce (Box 14)
- Miscellany: photographs, currency, diary, etc. (Box 15)
- Poland (Box 16-17)
- Russia (Box 18)
- Reports (Box 19-21)
- Silesia (Upper) (Box 22)
- Trade Notes (Box 23)
- Treaties (Box 24)
- Books, pamphlets, articles - A.R.A. Review; C.R.B. Bulletin; agriculture food needs; economic problems (Box 25)
- Pamphlets and articles, etc., relating to food (Box 26)
- New clippings - Relief Europe - Rubber Report - Misc. (Box 27)